Hello programmer. Welcome back to our SQL T2 series. So today we are going to explore the
powerful union operator in the SQL. So first of all, I can simply define for the SQL union
operator. SQL is used to combine the result of two or more select queries into a single
results and it's incredibly useful for merging data from the different source. So now let's
explore for how it works. So it's some example, okay. So first of all, I will create the combining
result from the two table. It is a simple example of combining the result from the two tables using
for the union operator, okay. So first of all, here describe select, then first again type,
here the first. So if I write the first name and also here I will create the last name column
from the employee stable, okay. The MPL or Y employee stable. And now here I am using the union
operator and now here I can just again type for here the select the first name and then the
last name and also here create for use for the from the stage name and here remove this one,
okay. I can only use for this and now just check for here the contractors, okay.
The contractor stable. So they find perfectly and now in this operate the mass result into two
select queries and first query select the names from the employee stable and second query select
from the names from the contractor stable, okay. So first of all, here select and then execute
and you can see here perfectly combine the merge for the employee's first name,
there you put on the last name, Zara and then Zara and the Jahan, okay. I hope you
perfect understand it and perfect work in the union statement, okay. So next step here I can use
for removing the duplicate columns, okay. So here I can use the department and from the employee
stable. So just remove this and then insert the department, okay. And also for just change here
and select then remove this department column, okay. You can see here this column is the department
column and here using for the unit to combine the department from the both table if there are
duplicate department, there will be automatically removed from the result set. So now just select
and execute now just execute and you can see perfectly remove the duplicate department column.
So you can see here the first department, the age and marketing and I hope you understand it
and next step here I can use for another example so here I can create the filtering for the results
set for the use the union operator, okay. So first of all here I can use just check again
that you can create for the first name, the column and then the last name for the
employee stable or I can use the where close from the here I can this is the department is equal
to now I can just choose the department of Iq, okay. So now just going again here and create the
constructor where the project is, okay. So project is equal to define for the project of x, okay.
So here this union to combine the names of the employees from the Iq department with the name of
the contractor working on the project x, okay. And select query as where the closed filter
the result becoming for the combining with the union, okay. So now just try C and here this
just I will show the options, okay. So just select all and then execute and now you can see here
this is not combining all the queries. So simply here we cannot define this Iq and it is not
combined and now simply open for the contractors table. So just go another query and here first of
all I can type the select then start from the contractors table, okay. Select all and then execute
and you can see here perfectly see constructor ID the first name and the last name.
The department and project and I can open for the employee table. So here I can just type
this is the employee and select all and execute. Now I hope you can see here not state for the
project column, okay. So now only you can see here the same column name but this is the contractor
table for the different or extra one column for the project column for the table not here,
okay. So I hope you understand and there you have it and what we have the union operator and
perfectly defined in this SQL use some practical example, okay. So if you find this tutorial helpful
stay tuned and thank you for watching and happy coding, okay.